Ruochen Wang (王若宸)

ruocwang@google.com / ruocwang@ucla.edu / ruocwang@umich.edu • 3108196039 Homepage: https://ruocwang.github.io/

Research Interests

I study the problem of AI for AI. The goal is to leverage the power of A.I. to automatize the development of itself. For the past two years, I have mainly focused on a prominent direction under this concept - Automated Machine Learning (AutoML), which includes:

- Neural Architecture Search (NAS)
- Optimize Search
- Dataset Compression (DC)

Education

01/2020 to	University of California at Los Angeles (UCLA)	U.S.
present •	Computer Science Department	
	Ph.D. in Computer Science; Advisor: Prof. Cho-Jui Hsieh	
	M.S. in Computer Science; GPA=4.0/4.0; Advisor: Prof Cho-Jui Hsieh	
09/2015 to	The University of Michigan-Ann Arbor (UMich)	U.S.
08/2019	Department of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science (EECS)	
	B.S. in Computer Science & B.S. in Statistics; GPA: 4.0/4.0	
09/2013 to	(Transferred) Shanghai University of Finance and Economics (SUFE)	China
06/2015	School of Finance	
	Financial Experimental Class; GPA: 3.93/4.0; Program Rank: 1/30	

Selected Honors

- Outstanding Graduate Student (for Master's degree, 1 per department), *UCLA CS Department*, 05/2022.
- Outstanding Paper Award, *ICLR 2021*, 04/2021.
- Award of Excellence (10%), *Microsoft Research Asia (MSRA)*, 09/2019.
- Highest Distinction Graduate Award, *The University of Michigan*, 08/2019.
- Berkeley Fung's Excellence Scholarship, *UC Berkeley Graduate Admission Committee*, 03/2019.
- Outstanding Intern Award, *SenseTime*, 01/2019.
- James B. Angell Scholar, *The University of Michigan*, 2017-2019.
- Shanghai City Scholarship (0.6%), *Shanghai City Government*, 09/2014.

Publications (1st-author marked blue)

- Ruochen Wang, Yuanhao Xiong, Minhao Cheng, Cho-Jui Hsieh. Efficient Non-Parametric Optimizer Search for Diverse Tasks. (*under review 2022*)
- Justin Cui, **Ruochen Wang**, Si Si, Cho-Jui Hsieh. DC-BENCH: Dataset Condensation benchmark. (*under review 2022*)
- Yuanhao Xiong*, Ruochen Wang*, Minhao Cheng, Cho-Jui Hsieh. FedDM: Iterative Distribution Matching for Communication-Efficient Federated Learning. (Arxiv 2022)
- Yuanhao Xiong, Li-Cheng Lan, Xiangning Chen, **Ruochen Wang**, Cho-Jui Hsieh. Learning to Schedule Learning rate with Graph Neural Networks. (*ICLR 2022*).
- Shoukang Hu*, Ruochen Wang*, Lanqing Hong, Zhenguo Li, Cho-Jui Hsieh, Jiashi Feng. Generalizing Few-Shot NAS with Gradient Matching. (* equal contribution) (*ICLR 2022*).
- Ruochen Wang, Xiangning Chen, Minhao Cheng, Xiaocheng Tang, Cho-Jui Hsieh. RANK-NOSH: Efficient Predictor-Based Architecture Search via Non-Uniform Successive Halving. (*ICCV 2021*).

- Ruochen Wang, Minhao Cheng, Xiangning Chen, Xiaocheng Tang, Cho-Jui Hsieh. Rethinking architecture selection in differentiable NAS. (*ICLR 2021*). Outstanding Paper Award.
- Xiangning Chen*, **Ruochen Wang***, Minhao Cheng*, Xiaocheng Tang, Cho-Jui Hsieh. DrNAS: Dirichlet Neural Architecture Search. (* equal contribution) (*ICLR 2021*).

Research Experience

05/2022 to **Google Research**

U.S.

Present

Student Researcher on ML Vision Synergy, with Dr. Boqing Gong and Dr. Ting Liu

• Developing efficient architectures for video dense prediction.

01/2020 to

UCLA Samueli School of Engineering

Los Angeles

Present

Graduate Student Researcher with Prof. Cho-Jui Hsieh

AutoML:

- Proposed the first efficient, scalable, and generalizable optimizer search framework for diverse tasks.
- Proposed a method to measure and alleviate the adverse effects of weight-sharing in One-Shot NAS;
 obtained <u>SOTA on all major NAS search spaces and datasets</u> (ICLR 2022).
- Proposed a scheduling algorithm and a learning-to-rank framework that reduce the search cost of predictor-based NAS by 5x while achieving the same search performance (ICCV 2021).
- Analyzed and explained the failure modes of Differentiable NAS from the long-overlooked architecture selection perspective (ICLR 2021 Oral, Outstanding Paper Award).
- Proposed (together with collaborators) a method to improve the robustness of differentiable NAS via Bayesian learning with Dirichlet distribution; derived a theoretical bound to prove the effectiveness of the proposed method utilizing Laplacian Approximation (ICLR 2021).

Dataset Learning:

- Investigating the effectiveness of Dataset Distillation for non-i.i.d. Federated Learning (under review).
- Co-developing a benchmark for Dataset Condensation methods. (under review).

Graph Neural Networks:

• Exploring stochastic learning algorithms for Graph Neural Networks (ongoing).

Transformers:

• Studying the efficiency and multimodality of Transformer models (ongoing).

05/2019 to

Microsoft Research

Beijing

09/2019

Research Intern

Neural Architecture Search:

• Conducted research on resource-constrained neural architecture search for production purposes.

Reinforcement Learning:

• Drafted a paper on improving the optimization of the Proximal Policy Gradient via Interior Point methods.

09/2018 to

SenseTime

Shanghai

03/2019

Research Intern

Adversarial Robustness:

• Conducted research on the <u>adversarial robustness in the frequency domain</u>; developed evolution and gradient-based method to generate adversarial frequencies.

09/2017 to

UMich College of Engineering

Ann Arbor

04/2018

Research Assistant with Prof. Honglak Lee

Vision Meets Language:

• Worked on <u>natural language queried object detection</u> with a word-sensitive discriminative bimodal network that aimed at solving dataset bias problems utilizing Bayesian reformulation.

Professional Services

Reviewer for ICML 2021~2022, NeurIPS 2021~2022, ICLR 2022~2023, TMLR